The most practical example of a Window function is a running total.
أكثر الأمثلة عملية على دالة النافذة هو المجموع التراكمي.
For example, let's say you want to calculate
مثلاً، لنقل أنك تريد احتساب
a running total of how much standard paper Parch and Posey
مجموع تراكمي لكمية الورق العادي
has sold to date.
الذي باعته Parch and Posey حتى تاريخه.
You can see that this query creates an aggregation,
نلاحظ أن هذا الاستعلام يخلق تجميعاً،
running total, without using group by.
وهو المجموع التراكمي، من دون استخدام GROUP BY.
Let's break down the syntax and see how it works.
لنقسّم بناء الجملة إلى أجزاء ونتعرف على طريقة عملها.
The first part of this aggregation looks a lot like any other aggregation.
يشبه أول جزء من هذا التجميع أي عملية تجميع أخرى إلى حد كبير.
Adding over, designates it as a Window function.
إضافة OVER تجعله أنها دالة نافذة.
You could read the above aggregation as,
يمكنك قراءة التجميع أعلاه كالتالي:
take the sum of standard quantity,
احسب مجموع الورق standard_qty
across all rows leading up to a given row,
بجمع جميع الصفوف وصولاً إلى صف معيّن،
in order by occurred at.
بالترتيب وفقاً لقيم العمود occurred_at.
Let's say that instead,
لنفترض بدلاً من ذلك
we want to start the running total over at the beginning of each month.
أننا نريد إعادة احتساب المجموع التراكمي مع بداية كل شهر.
To narrow the window from the entire dataset to individual groups within a data set,
لتضييق النافذة من مجموعة البيانات الكاملة إلى مجموعات فردية ضمن مجموعة البيانات،
you use the partition by function.
نستخدم دالة PARTITION BY.
Now this query groups and orders the query
الآن أصبح هذا الاستعلام يجمّع نتائج الاستعلام ويرتّبها
by the month in which the transaction occurred.
حسب الشهر الذي حصلت فيه الحركة.
Within each month, it's ordered by occurred at.
وضمن كل شهر يتم ترتيبها حسب occurred_at.
And the running total,
والمجموع التراكمي
sums across that current row and all previous rows of standard quantity.
يجمع الصفّ الحالي وكافة الصفوف السابقة لـ standard_qty.
That's what happens when you group using partition by.
هذا ما يحدث عندما تقوم بضم الصفوف باستخدام PARTITION BY.
In case you're still stumped by order by,
في حال ما زلت تجد صعوبة في فهم عمل ORDER BY هنا،
it simply orders the designated columns the same way the order by clause would,
فهي ببساطة ترتب الأعمدة المحددة بنفس الطريقة التي ترتبها بها ORDER BY،
except that it treats every partition as separate.
باستثناء أنها تعامل كل قسم على أنه منفصل عن البقي.
It also creates the running total.
كما أنها تُنتج المجموع التراكمي أيضاً.
Without order by, each value will simply be
من دون ORDER BY، ستكون كل قيمة
a sum of all the standard quantity values in its respective month.
مجرد مجموع جميع قيم standard_qty في الشهر الذي ترتبط به.
To get a clearer picture,
لتوضيح الصورة أكثر،
here's what happens when we run this query without order by.
هذا ما يحصل عندما ننفذ هذا الاستعلام من دون ORDER BY.
The order and partition defined what's referred to as the window.
يحدد الترتيب والتقسيم ما نسميه بالنافذة. 00:02:40,200 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 أي المجموعة الفرعية المرتبة من البيانات التي يتم إجراء كل هذه الحسابات عليها.